thetrainline-europe.com 2016-05-15

# Privacy policy - thetrainline europe

Your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy sets out the procedures Trainline International Limited has in place in relation to the collection, use and disclosure of information you may provide or we may collect via this Website and the Services.

### Your Consent

By using these Services, you agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy and whenever you submit information via the Website you consent to the collection, use and disclosure of that information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### Active Collection of Information

Some areas of the Website require you to actively submit information in order for you to benefit from specific features or make a booking. Some of this information may be personal (namely, information that can identify you, such as your name or email address). We only collect such information when you choose to supply it to us. You confirm that you will only enter information about yourself and that such information is true.

### Passive Collection of Information

We may collect and process anonymous information about your use of the Services, such as some of the pages you visit and some of the searches you perform. Such information is used by us to help us improve the contents of the site and to compile, for internal market research purposes, aggregate statistics about individuals using it. This kind of anonymous information can be obtained by our use of “cookies”. Please see our ‘Cookies’ section below for more information on our use of cookies.

We may also share anonymous information about your use of the TLi Booking Service with third parties for analytical purposes.

### Cookies

We use “cookies” and other similar anonymous tracking technologies on our Website in order to distinguish you from other users of our Website and to help provide you with a good experience when you use our Website. A “cookie” is a small piece of information that is stored within your browser and allows us to identify those requests to our Website that originate from your computer, and sometimes provide additional information such as your recent searches on our Website. We also work with third parties who use cookies and other similar anonymous tracking technologies, including but not limited to web beacons, on our Website to collect browser and other information. We also direct you to third parties who use cookies and other similar anonymous tracking technologies on their websites to complete your booking and collect browser and other information. We are not responsible for the cookie practices of such third parties when you leave our site. You should read the cookie policy of each third party.

Most web browsers allow you to configure your browser settings to refuse all or some cookies. How you do this will depend on the web browser you use but we have set out a step-by-step guide to the most popular browsers in our dedicated [cookies page](http://travel.thetrainline-europe.com/cookies/). However, if you use your browser setting to block all cookies you will not be able to access all or parts of our Website.

For more information about cookies generally and the different types of cookies that we use on our Website, please see our dedicated [cookies page](http://travel.thetrainline-europe.com/cookies/). By using our Website you agree that you are aware of and understand that cookies are used on our Website (including cookies which are set and controlled by third parties) and the purposes for which they are used. Our dedicated cookies page forms an integral part of this Privacy Policy.

### Use of Information Collected

We will only use your personal information in line with the consent you have given and/or in accordance with this Privacy Policy. Your personal information submitted to us is used for operational purposes (for example, assisting you to book rail and non-rail, confirming your itinerary via email if you have consented to that and have provided your email address for that purpose, producing rail tickets and delivering them to you by your chosen means, processing payments or confirming bookings) and to personalise your shopping experience when browsing by using your purchases and browsing activity to make recommendations to you about products and services that we think may be of interest to you. We will not use your email address for marketing purposes unless you have specifically consented to such use. Visa and MasterCard transactions are processed by Trainline.com Limited, 15, Rue Edward Steichen, L-2540, Luxembourg, 4th Floor. Registered in Luxembourg, RCS B 171.363

We and/or our authorised third parties may also use your personal information: (a) for internal market research and analysis purposes; and (b) to carry out survey related activities with you.

### Sharing of Information

We may share your personal information with third party service providers (including service providers outside of the EU) for the purpose of: (a) processing a booking reservation, taking payment for a booking or otherwise in relation to fulfilling a booking you have made via the TLi Booking Service; (b) for marketing services (where you have consented to receive such marketing services); (c) for processing payment (including fraud screening); (d) advertising; and (e) for undertaking any other permitted use of your personal information on our behalf. These service providers will only have access to the personal information needed to perform the applicable service and may not use your personal information for any other purpose. Our nominated third parties will also be required to use your personal information strictly in accordance with data protection laws, including maintaining adequate security measures to protect such personal information.

If you wish to make bookings of rail products for rail journeys that originate and/or terminate in Germany you will provide personal data to us which we will pass on to Deutsche Bahn for it to process your booking reservation and take payment or otherwise deal with your personal data as set out in Deutsche Bahn’s terms and conditions (which will be made accessible to you prior to you completing your booking).

If you wish to make bookings or buy products or services via the Referral Service you will be directed to the applicable third party provider and you will inevitably provide personal data to that third party provider. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. When you leave our site, we encourage you to read the privacy statements/policies of each and every website that collects personal data from you. This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by us via this Website.

We may share your personal information with (a) any person who takes over our business to use your personal information on the same basis as we do; or (b) third parties (including service providers outside of the EU) which provide services to us solely to assist us to provide the Services to you; or (c) legal or regulatory authorities where we are lawfully requested or required to do so, or voluntarily to the Police and similar law enforcement agencies (including fraud prevention and detection), other government agencies or third parties. We may also share your personal information with third parties (including service providers outside of the EU) who assist us with marketing to you (but only if you have opted in to us marketing to you) or which provide us with web analytics services which enable us to customise and develop the Services. However, we will never sell or give away your personal information or use it other than as provided under this Privacy Policy.

Trainline International Limited and its third party service providers may further use your personal information: (a) for analysis and market research related services; (b) to carry out survey related activities with you; and (c) to contact you about new features, services, products and special offers in line with the consent you have provided. If you initially wish to receive such material but you change your mind later, you may tell us by sending us an email to feedback@thetrainline-europe.com. Please check the privacy policy of the third party rail provider you travel with for further details as to how that third party uses your personal information.

Where we direct you to third party websites for you to make bookings, we may use your personal information to pre-fill selected details within the third party website in order to make the booking process easier and more efficient for you.

### Use of location data

Information about your location or approximate location may be used by us when providing the Services. We obtain and use this information in two main ways:

**Internet traffic information, such as your IP address:** This information is provided automatically as you use our Services and can allow us to infer your approximate location – for example your city and country. We use this information:

  * for analysis purposes to understand the distribution of our customers and in order to refer you to the appropriate third party as part of our Referral Service;
  * to prevent false or fraudulent card transactions;
  * to tailor messages or advertisements shown on our Website – for example if we identify that you are likely to be located in London, we may show you promotions relating to journeys starting in London.

**Location information provided by your browser or device:** Many web browsers, particularly on mobile phones and tablet devices, are able to accurately report your location, for example using GPS technology. The same is true for apps on mobile phones and tablets. These browsers and devices normally ask your permission before sharing your location with a website or app, and you can usually disable the feature altogether in the device settings. We use this information for features that need to know your location.

### Security

We take the security of your data very seriously. We employ physical, electronic and administrative security measures to protect the information that we collect about you from access by unauthorised persons and against unlawful processing, accidental loss, destruction and damage. You acknowledge and agree that we shall not be responsible for any unauthorised use, distribution, damage or destruction of personal data, except to the extent we are required to accept such responsibility by the data protection laws.

### Links to Third Party Internet Sites

The Website contains links to other sites and sources of information. By clicking on these, you will leave the Website and this Privacy Policy will not apply to your use of any other sites.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

There may be changes in how we use your data. All such changes will be notified to you by updating this Privacy Policy.

### Access to Personal Information

You are entitled to see the personal information we hold about you and may obtain these details by writing to us at: thetrainline-europe.com, c/o Trainline International Limited, PO Box 24052, Edinburgh, EH3 1EL. We are entitled by law to charge an administrative fee to meet our costs in providing you with such details and we may require proof of your identity before we supply the information to you.
